Hey, everybody. Welcome to this B1
English listening practice video. You
can use this video to practice your
listening and comprehension as I speak.
Before we start, remember to download
the Listening Time podcast. And if you
want my specialized training to help you
improve your listening, then become a
member at patreon.com/listeningtime.
If you become a member, you'll receive
my seminars, which will help you listen
more effectively and understand native
speakers. And if you become a Listening
Time family member, then you'll receive
my advanced podcast, which will help you
reach an advanced level of listening.
Okay, today I'm going to talk about the
concept of having a midlife crisis. This
is something that I've talked about a
couple times recently, and so I thought
it would be a good topic to discuss
here. So, first of all, what is a
midlife crisis? Well, according to some
definitions, it's an emotional crisis
involving one's identity and
self-confidence. This usually happens
somewhere between the age of 40 and 60,
but it could happen a little before or
after this. So, during this crisis, the
person often questions their own life
choices, their identity, and their
desires. They've already lived around
half their life, and they might not be
happy with where they're at. It's
understandable, really. Let's talk about
some of the different areas of life that
people tend to question or change during
this period. First, let's talk about
finances. A lot of people feel really
stressed financially during their
adulthood. Not only do they need to
provide for themselves and any family
they have, they also need to think about
their children's future expenses, their
own retirement, and plenty of other
things. Thus, it's normal to feel like
you're just barely getting by
financially. And when you're feeling
this way in your 40s or 50s, it's
especially stressful. People often
expect to be thriving financially during
these years, so it's a big blow to them
when this doesn't happen. But, it's
normal to have a lot of expenses during
this time. I think many of us are going
to deal with this. Something else that
contributes to midlife crises is
changing family dynamics. In the US,
it's common for kids to move out of
their parents' house at a relatively
young age. This means that a lot of
people in their 40s and 50s become empty
nesters, as we call them. This just
means that they have adult children who
have already moved out. This can be a
difficult transition for parents, seeing
as they spent so much of their focus and
energy on raising their children. Once
they move out, their parents can feel a
little bit empty and experience negative
emotions. So, this is a challenge that
people have to overcome. Another factor
that plays a role in midlife crises is a
person's physical changes. When people
start to feel their body changing with
age, it can be hard to deal with. We
like to think of ourselves as healthy
and fit, and so it's hard for us to
experience a physical decline. It's not
cool to feel like we can't do all the
things we used to do, and it can cause
people to worry about their future
health. So, this might drive people to
become more active and get in shape. One
other factor involved in midlife crises
is people's sense of accomplishment. If
you feel like you haven't achieved a lot
by this time, you can get discouraged.
We all want to feel like we've done
great things and served a higher
purpose. So, people might change their
career during a midlife crisis because
they want to do something more
meaningful. So, a lot of this sounds
pretty negative, but people eventually
get through this period. Once they can
accept these changes and get refocused,
they can work through this challenging
time and become stronger as a result.
All right, that's all for today.
Remember to download the Listening Time
podcast and become a member at
patreon.com/listeningtime
to receive my specialized listening
training to help you understand native
speakers. And if you want to reach an
advanced level of listening, then become
a Listening Time family member to
receive my advanced podcast. The link is
in the description below this video.
Also, subscribe to the channel, click on
the bell, and follow us on Instagram.
I'll see you next time.